<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interaction in Virtual and Augmented Reality</title>
    <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Interaction in Virtual and Augmented Reality</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interaction - Translation</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/05-interaction-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/05-interaction-translation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locomotion III - Tuning Values</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/04-locomotion-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/04-locomotion-iii/</guid>
      <description>This chapter is mostly about making small adjustments based on personal impression of the locomotion system after initial testing, as well as incrementally fine-tuning the values to improve the movement itself.
General Changes I did end up enabling &amp;lsquo;strafing&amp;rsquo; by tilting your head on the forward (z) axis. This turned out to be somewhat confusing, but manageable, when standing still, but made precise course adjustments when moving at a faster pace much easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locomotion II - Turning</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/03-locomotion-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/03-locomotion-ii/</guid>
      <description>As you may have noticed already, the movement implementation of the previous chapter has one integral flaw: There is no way to actually rotate around the up-axis in order to turn around farther than a normal person&amp;rsquo;s neck allows. As this project is intended to help people with severely reduced freedom of movement, 360° full body turning may not be a possibility, and the turning angle needs to be defined by the maximum angle the neck can turn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locomotion I - Headset Angles &amp; Basic Movement</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/02-locomotion-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/02-locomotion-i/</guid>
      <description>To develop the locomotion technique, I set up a simple testing scene to enable controlled testing without needing to deploy the entire Parkour-Scene everytime. The scene is currently incredibly simple, yet provides everything needed to test a simple character-controller: Collisions and a slope.
Unity Testing Scene: Everything a man needs to survive. Also, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to correctly scale materials independant of the mesh it&amp;rsquo;s applied to, so this scene uses around 20 materials with the same texture and different scaling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Unity for Quest2 development.</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/01-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/01-setup/</guid>
      <description>Headset Configuration Before beginning to develop software for the Quest2, we need to setup the headset and corresponding software.
Quest2 First, enable development mode on the Headset. Unfortunately, in order to do this, a Smartphone with the Oculus-App is required. After installing the App and logging into your Meta-Account, pair your Phone to the Quest2. Make sure the Phone and Quest are in the same WiFi network, both have bluetooth enabled, your phone having location services enabled, and both devices being situated close to one another and the router.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mostly Hands-Free Interaction in VR - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/00-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somedudeonthispage.github.io/TUDA-InteractionVR-Blog/post/00-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This entire blog is about &amp;lsquo;Interaction in Virtual and augmented Reality&amp;rsquo;, a course at TU-Darmstadt in the winter semester 2022/2023, in which I participated. More details can be (hopefully, in case TUCAN, the universities&amp;rsquo; system, didn&amp;rsquo;t die) found here. The course was held by Jan Gugenheimer1, the overall class structure was inspired by the MIT-Course &amp;ldquo;How to make (almost) Anything&amp;rdquo;2, a course in which people&amp;hellip; make&amp;hellip; stuff&amp;hellip; and then write about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
